LAURA D. HAMILTON

420 East Waterside, Apartment 708 Chicago, Illinois 60601 312.523.6340 lauradhamilton@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Proven product manager with a track record of launching new businesses quickly and delivering stellar results. Successfully launched 3 international businesses (UK, Australia & Canada) and a US installment product; promoted 3 times in a 3-year span due to ability to deliver results.

Extensive experience with e-commerce, software-development lifecycle and internet marketing (SEM, SEO, scrum, agile development, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL).

EXPERIENCE

CASH AMERICA INTERNATIONAL

Chicago, Illinois

Publicly traded financial services company (NYSE ticker: CSH) focused on under-banked consumers.

Senior Manager, Product Management

August 2009 – Present

- Launched UK installment business on time due to detailed management and laser-like focus on key issues
 - Led team of 4 developers and 4 tech QA personnel to launch product in 5 months
 - Business ramped to \$10MM revenue run rate within 3 months, with projected revenue of \$100MM in 2012
 - Performed data analysis of customer database to create rules for identifying existing customers
 - Drove selection of brand name based on market research, including trademark search and registration
- Launched Canadian business in October 2009
 - Led troubleshooting to correct payments issues, reducing payment delinquencies by 18 percentage points
- Managed two new product managers to independently own their own products within 3 months

Product Manager, Product Management

August 2008 – August 2009

- Managed company's expansion efforts into Australia in May 2009
 - Coordinated operational, technical, financial, legal, and marketing aspects of the launch
 - Built technical specifications for complex transactional logic to support brokered lending
- Launched a US-based installment product, actively managing it to profitability within 3 months
 - Identified system bugs based on quantitative analyses and sitting with call center staff

Senior Associate, Strategic Initiatives

November 2007 – August 2008

• Negotiated new vendor contract for underwriting tool that generated \$250K a year savings (lower defaults)

SUSQUEHANNA INTERNATIONAL GROUP

Bala Cynwyd, Pennsylvania

One of the largest options trading firm in the world responsible for $\sim 15\%$ of daily listed equity options volume.

Assistant Trader

June 2006 – September 2007

- Aggregated the firm's risk in NDX- related products (options, futures, ETFs and stock baskets)
- Developed a statistical model to predict a hospital's credit score based on financial data

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO

Chicago, Illinois June 2006

Bachelor of Arts, double major in Math and Economics

- Graduated in 3 years with GPA of 3.6/4.0
- National Merit Scholar and SAT of 1590 (800 verbal and 790 math)
- Copy editor and columnist for the Chicago Maroon (2003 to 2006)
- Studied abroad in Barcelona and Paris

ACTIVITIES & INTERESTS

- Running, rock-climbing, skiing, hiking; most recent hiking experience was Haleakala's Sliding Sands trail
- Passionate (and currently very sad) Bears fan